<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shell on Paulius.uk</title>
    <link>https://paulius.uk/tags/shell/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Shell on Paulius.uk</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 12:55:56 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://paulius.uk/tags/shell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Managing Docker Containers</title>
      <link>https://paulius.uk/posts/2024/docker-containers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 12:55:56 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulius.uk/posts/2024/docker-containers/</guid>
      <description>What is Docker? Docker is a platform that allows developers to create, deploy, and run applications in containers. These containers encapsulate the application and its dependencies, ensuring consistent and reproducible environments across different systems. With Docker, developers can easily share and deploy applications without worrying about compatibility issues or complex setup processes.&#xA;Docker Management Managing Docker environments efficiently involves not only cleaning up but also creating and maintaining containers, images, volumes, and more.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Networking Commands and Troubleshooting</title>
      <link>https://paulius.uk/posts/2024/network-commands/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 16:20:46 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulius.uk/posts/2024/network-commands/</guid>
      <description>Networking Commands for Windows and Linux Networking commands are essential for diagnosing, troubleshooting, and managing network-related issues on both Windows and Linux systems. Here, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore some commonly used networking commands and their usage on both platforms, as well as troubleshooting steps to resolve common network problems.&#xA;Network Troubleshooting Steps Check Hardware Use ipconfig (or ifconfig) Use ping and tracert (traceroute) Perform DNS check Check for Virus/Malware Review Database Logs Contact ISP (Internet Service Provider) Additional Steps:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Linux &#34;chmod&#34; commands</title>
      <link>https://paulius.uk/posts/2024/chmod/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 14:15:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulius.uk/posts/2024/chmod/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s Explore Linux chmod Commands: 400, 600, 644, 700, 777, and the &amp;ldquo;s&amp;rdquo; Bit. In the Linux operating system, file permissions are crucial for controlling access to files and directories. The chmod command is used to modify these permissions. Understanding the numeric values associated with file permissions is essential for managing security effectively. Here, we&amp;rsquo;ll delve into six common chmod commands: 400, 600, 644, 700, and 777, and introduce the significance of the &amp;ldquo;s&amp;rdquo; bit, explaining its usage.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bandit overthewire.org</title>
      <link>https://paulius.uk/posts/2024/bandit-overthewire.org/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 16:12:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulius.uk/posts/2024/bandit-overthewire.org/</guid>
      <description>Level Solution Description Password Level 0 ssh bandit0@bandit.labs.overthewire.org -p 2220 ssh into server with port 2220. show pass bandit0 Level 0 → Level 1 cat readme The password for the next level is stored in a file called readme. show pass NH2SXQwcBdpmTEzi3bvBHMM9H66vVXjL Level 1 → Level 2 cat ./- The password for the next level is stored in a file called - located in the home directory. show pass rRGizSaX8Mk1RTb1CNQoXTcYZWU6lgzi Level 2 → Level 3 cat &amp;ldquo;spaces in this filename&amp;rdquo; The password for the next level is stored in a file called spaces in this filename located in the home directory.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
